Jose Ramon Alonso Tapia CURRICULUM

SUMMARY

Degree in Electronics, but always worked as a Software Engineer, both in **Spain and in England**.

Main experience is in C, Linux, Java and scripting languages.

Currently learning web technologies (HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Nodejs, Angular, Django and more) in order to become a competent **full-stack web developer**.

As a **long time Linux user**, I am a frequent self-learner and a very inquisitive person. I self taught GNU/Linux, as well as Perl and regular expressions.

Contact Details

Email -----> jose.alonso.programmer@gmail.com

LinkedIn -----> https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseramonalonsotapia/

Github -----> https://github.com/josealonso

EDUCATION

2017 - 2018 Web Startup Engineering Bootcamp in KeepCoding

- * Git and GitHub
- * Front-end Development: HTML5, CSS3 and **JavaScript**. Ajax, Grunt/Gulp, SASS, RWD.
- * Advanced Backend Development with **Node.js** and with Python/Django.
- * DevOps with Node.js.
- * Angular 4.
- * Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, ElasticSearch. Microservicies with Docker.
- * UX + IA. SEO + Google Analytics + Social Media SCRUM and Agile methodologies.
- * Web Components and Polymer. Frameworks: ReactJS, Electron, Ionic.

2004 - 2008 Studies of Engineer in Electronics

University of Alcala, Madrid, Spain.

- Operating Systems, Real-Time Systems and Ada language, The Linux Kernel.
- Theory of microprocessors, types of caches.
- Communications.
- Computer Networks (TCP/IP), Control Systems, Semiconductor Devices, Heavy Mathematics.

2003 Studies in the University of Alabama, United States

Exchange student, thanks to a scholarship granted by my university in Spain.

Some courses on Computer Science and Electronics.

2001 Erasmus Student in Sweden

Final Degree Project: Programming in assembly language an application for the Microchip PIC16F84 microcontroller.

1996 - 2001 Engineering in Industrial Electronics

University of Alcala, Madrid, Spain.

• Bachelor's degree in Electronics.

EMPLOYMENT

Embedded Software Engineer

Jan 2015 - Oct 2016

LEAR at Tarragona, Spain.

Embedded Software Engineer for automotive systems. C Programmer and System Validation Engineer.

Embedded Software Engineer Jun 2014 – Sept 2015

KBioSystems Ltd. at Basildon, United Kingdom. Automation sector.

Programming in C the ARM Cortex-M microcontroller, using an Eclipsebased IDE. Also programming a tactile display that communicates with mentioned microcontroller. Topics: interaction between hardware and software, driving stepper and **DC motors**, using the **RS232** and the **CAN** communication protocols.

Software Engineer

Jun 2013 - Jan 2014

Glasswall Solutions at Chelmsford, United Kingdom.

Programming in a C-based, non-procedural language.

I occasionally used **Perl** and **Python**. I mentored some placement students.

Java Programmer

Jan 2012 - Jul 2012

Personal project. Java Swing application to generate Latex-based curricula.

I learned **Latex**, bibtex, Java programming and how an event-driven graphical application works.

Work in Madrid, Spain

2007 - 2010

Main duties: Linux administrator and analyst programmer in C/C+ +.

Technologies: gcc toolchain, scripting in Linux and in Windows, Java, databases, Version Control Systems.